PETRI YAM<u>AMOTO</u>

SKILLS

Oracle · Communication Skills ·

Angular · Hibernate · AWS · APis · J2Ee

INDUSTRY EXPERTISE

Client - Focused Work!!!

LANGUAGES

English

Native

AWARDS

Dev of the Quarter (Q3/2015) at Crazy Lazy Apps

Full Stack Java Developer

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic and well-organized Java developer with 3+ years of experience. Eager to join Infiltrix to bring in top-class Java development and problem-solving skills. In previous roles reduced app memory consumption by 30%, and decreased startup time for Java-powered apps by 70%.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

05/2015 - 06/2018

Citiustech

Location

Company Description

- Produced custom applications, frameworks and components to solve unique business problems
- Designed new features for existing applications and implemented them into production
- Determined the best programming languages and tools to use for future projects and provided recommendations for tool selection
- Created a software development process and team workflow to ensure future development projects are built in a repeatable, efficient and reliable fashion

Sr Java/J2Ee Developer

06/2018 - 03/2021

HCL Singapore Pte Ltd

Location

Company Description

- Optimized the development of new web applications to reduce development time by 30%
- Increased the number of active users on the website by 60% and increased page views to 1.5 million page views per month
- Created an inventory management system that reduced the time to capture data by 80% and reduced the number of errors by 40%
- Managed developers to ensure they were delivering new features on time and with high quality
- Assisted a team of 2 developers in the development of a mobile application for the company's website
- Supported the development of a series of new web applications for the company's business unit

Sr. Java Developer

03/2021 - Ongoing

Hewlet

Location

Company Description

- Extracted and analyzed data sets from the previous year's analytics reports
- Designed a new data model and database schema to meet the needs of the business, optimizing the company's processes and cost structure
- Developed a survey among customers to better understand their requirements and improve their digital experience
- Identified opportunities for new products and services by assessing industry trends, competitor analysis and customer feedback

EDUCATION

Computer Science

01/2014

National University of Singapore